<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts. Insights. Life lessons.</title>
    <description>Pen down the incomprehensibly complex life experiences which will, otherwise, get lost in silence. Forever.
</description>
    <link>http://anandsoni.in</link>
    <atom:link href="http://anandsoni.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 19:06:29 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 19:06:29 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Introvert Professional</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introversion&lt;/em&gt; is a heavily misunderstood term in our times. An introvert is someone who tends to &lt;em&gt;turn inwards&lt;/em&gt; more than outwards. Introversion is not synonymous to being shy, timid or to any other word that disparages it. There has been a lot of talk and debate around introversion and extroversion in the past few decades. Though, I must say the world has come a long way from completely abhorring and discarding intoversion (and introverts) but still the path of an introvert isn’t all velvety petals in our society. I specifically intend to voice out my belief on this debate when it comes to the path tread by an &lt;em&gt;introvert professional&lt;/em&gt;. Why focus only on the &lt;em&gt;introvert professional&lt;/em&gt;? Does this mean anything about &lt;em&gt;other introverts&lt;/em&gt; having an easy plod through the mud? No. Being a professional, it interests me to talk about what I have seen and experienced around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-the-introvert-extrovert-debate-in-such-limelight&quot;&gt;Why is the introvert-extrovert debate in such limelight?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terms introversion and extroversion were coined and popularized in the 1920s by the renowned Swiss psychiatrist Carl Jung. Personality tests existed before 1920 but ever since these terms were coined, we started to distinguish between personalities in subtle ways. Just like America had existed before Columbus’ voyage, introverts and extroverts existed before Jung christened them. But only in a more ignorant manner. Indeed, ignorance was bliss. And post 1920, introversion and extroversion became more overt as personality types (personality divides).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, how and why does this matter to an introvert professional? We live in a global society. Our society is a result of great voyages, wars, discoveries, inventions, migrations, knowledge sharing, DNA sharing and wealth transfer across and among the citizens of the world. Due to such globalization, people today are poised to deal, work or live with other people with different personalities and (code of) conduct, leading to rigorous experiences as well as creating a divide. In the professional world, this divide becomes more pronounced. &lt;em&gt;Introvert professionals&lt;/em&gt; live this divide every day and every working hour. How, you ask?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introvert--to-be-or-not-to-be&quot;&gt;Introvert : To be or not to be?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the modern days, (any) profession demands team players. Not only that, but the modern education system is so focused on “building” team players that it is not rare to see introverts feeling lost in the crowd. What we (in schools or industries) forget sometimes is to give more value to ideas rather than words. It is not about revamping the whole education system or the professional culture. On the contrary, it is about learing to accept and learning to give space. As Susan Cain aptly puts in &lt;em&gt;Quiet&lt;/em&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Solitude matters, and for some people, it’s the air they breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There’s zero correlation between being the best talker and having the best ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against the popular belief, it is not that an &lt;em&gt;introvert professional&lt;/em&gt; is afraid of being surrounded by people (meetings &amp;amp; discussions). Infact, most of them enjoy deep discussions. We only need to understand that after some time, they need their own space and time to think; to be productive. They need to go back home. This is their way of rejuvenating and refilling themselves. The industry and the education system needs to learn and respect it. Introversion is not something to prevent or cure. Again, an eye-opener from &lt;em&gt;Quiet&lt;/em&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Introverts, in contrast, may have strong social skills and enjoy parties and business meetings, but after a while wish they were home in their pajamas. They prefer to devote their social energies to close friends, colleagues, and family. They listen more than they talk, think before they speak, and often feel as if they express themselves better in writing than in conversation. They tend to dislike conflict. Many have a horror of small talk, but enjoy deep discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in essence, the question &lt;em&gt;to be or not to be&lt;/em&gt; is ruthless. If we even need to answer this question, may be we are not mature enough to understand and value introversion. For any &lt;em&gt;introvert&lt;/em&gt;, professional or not, the secret is to be true to what you are. No matter what, people will want you “not to be you”. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If you enjoy depth, don’t force yourself to seek breadth.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adaptation-and-the-art-of-flexing&quot;&gt;Adaptation and the art of flexing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, the path of an introvert is not all velvety petals. Expecting the world to learn is a Utopian idea. In the good old times (may be a few hundred years ago), people loved to mind their own business. A typical day for a teacher would be to deal with his regular students. A typical day for a businessman would be to deal with a few of his regular customers and go back home. A more &lt;em&gt;vegetative state&lt;/em&gt; prevailed in the society. The randomness that people deal with today, in their daily chores has grown (probably) exponentially in the past few hundred years. Much more than ever before, today, we live and work with people of different nationality, tastes and personality types. This difference, is emphatically pronouced in the modern professional world. And its very existence, in my opinion, leads to comparison and ultimately to the personality debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in order to excel in the professional world (I am talking about excellence not success), it is only very overt that both introverts and extroverts (especially introverts) need to adapt and learn the art of flexing. Although remember that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;flexing doesn’t mean changing yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It means adapting to situations to let yourself be heard and respected. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flexing is being practical and not being stubborn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. And it is definitley not easy. But, how exactly to flex and how it works? More on this later. Stay tuned. And remember to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;stay true to who you are.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://anandsoni.in/2016/07/31/introvert-professional/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://anandsoni.in/2016/07/31/introvert-professional/</guid>
        
        <category>Introversion</category>
        
        <category>Extroversion</category>
        
        <category>Professional</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
